[indistinct announcement over Tannoy]
Hey, hey! Hello, mate.
- Oh, it's good to see you.
- You too.
- How are you?
- Great.
Luke, this is my girlfriend, Suzie.
Suzie, Luke.
- Hi. It's so nice to meet you.
- And you know my sister Kate.
- Kate.
- Luke.
- Looking good.
- Thanks. I'll take that.
- Thank you.
- Let's go.
- [Kate] Wow, you really bought a car?
- [Luke] No.
After our sail, I've gotta deliver
the boat to lndonesia,
and the guy who's crewing for me
owns this.
- We're not keeping you from delivering?
- No, it's all good.
I can't believe you get to sail around
the world delivering boats for a living.
How fantastic.
Go introduce yourselves to Wazza.
The scruffy-looking one
fishing off a yacht.
- Cool.
- Great.
[Luke] See you soon.
So how have you been?
Good. Good. You?
Yeah, good. I'm going to get
some spark plugs. You wanna come?
Sure.
- Shane.
- Hey.
- Is Lou here?
- Yeah, he's just out the back.
- [Luke] Hey, Lou.
- [Lou] Yeah, out here!
- It's pretty impressive.
- Yeah.
That's a mako, tiger, hammerhead.
And that one's a white pointer.
Where'd you get these?
- Out there.
- Here?
Yeah. Strange about
the white pointer, though.
People reckon
they don't usually come this far north.
Don't worry. What do they say?
You're more likely to die from
a bee sting than get killed by a shark.
- Wazza.
- Hey.
- [Luke] Kate. Kate, Warren.
- Hi.
- How you going?
- Good.
- Welcome aboard.
- It's not bad.
- She's a bit scruffy, but she'll do.
I'll show you where you're sleeping.
This brings back memories.
- This is yours.
- Hey, so... I bought you something.
I wonder what this could be?
Thank you.
I really miss you.
- Sorry.
- It's OK.
- Is there someone else?
- No, there's nobody else. It's just...
You wanted a break
and now you're back.
Matt really wanted me to come,
and a holiday sounded like a good idea.
So that's what this is,
it's just a holiday?
Yeah, yeah, I'm here for a holiday.
OK. Good.
I've gotta go up.
Wanna catch the outgoing tide.
OK.
Oh, wow. Did you just catch that?
Yep. These waters are full of 'em.
- Cool.
- You in from Sydney?
Yeah, my brother and his girlfriend
are here from London.
And you're crewing with Luke
to lndonesia?
- Yeah.
- Have you crewed with him before?
No. No, this is the first time.
I usually work the fishing boats.
Thought I'd try something different.
- You've crewed with him, haven't you?
- How do you know that?
- He talks a bit about you.
- Oh.
Yeah, yeah, we sailed
the Mediterranean together.
- [rattling]
- Whoa! Looks like we're off.
So where are we heading?
Cygnet Reef. I wanna try and get there
by this afternoon.
Sounds great. What's there?
You'll see.
Hey, we're here.
- You good? See you.
- [women] Bye!
Have fun!
See you soon.
- [squeals]
- Sorry.
- You all right?
- Yeah.
Come with me.
Wow.
Wow, wow.
- How was that?
- Amazing.
- Is this your favourite spot?
- Actually, I've never been here before.
- Wanna go for a bit of an explore?
- Yep.
[chatter, laughter]
No.
Oh.
Look what I found.
Beautiful.
What?
I don't know.
Is this just sex
or is it something else?
I don't know.
You know what I think?
I think you're scared.
- Scared?
- Mm-hm.
- Scared of what?
- Me.
You. Us.
No, that's not it.
What is it, then?
I don't know.
- Come on, Kate, what?
- I don't know.
One minute we're having a good time,
and now we're not.
- I'll tell you what I think.
- I don't really care what you think.
Hey, Luke, Kate!
There's something up with Warren.
- [Warren yells]
- Tide's dropping really fast.
We hit bottom.
Kate, can you keep an eye out?
- I think it's leaking.
- Eh?
- [Warren] You're scraping.
- The tide's dropping really fast.
[Warren] I tried the engine.
She won't start.
- [Luke] OK, try now.
- Nothing.
- [Luke] Now.
- No, nothing.
Jump on the anchor.
Katie, can you get the sail, please?
Yeah.
Channel's opened up!
OK, I think we're out of trouble.
Thanks, guys.
Hey, Waz,
take a look at that engine, yeah?
Katie, steer.
- Sure.
- Keep her straight, yeah?
- We'll just keep it straight.
- [Matt] Yeah.
So, who wants a go?
- Suze?
- Me?
- Yeah, come on. Chance of a lifetime.
- Go on. Go on.
Two hands.
Good.
- Sailing.
- Hey!
Arr! Arr!
Hey. Thought I'd come up
and catch the morning.
It's gorgeous.
I'm really sorry about yesterday.
Yeah. Me too.
- It's tricky, isn't it?
- Yeah.
You don't have any doubts about us?
Plenty.
It's just, you know,
I really missed you.
I really missed you too.
- You hungry?
- Starving.
- Brekky?
- Yes, please.
Matt! Warren!
You all right? We've gotta
get out of here. It could go down.
Where's Matt? Matt? Matt?
[gasping]
Luke! Matt!
Oh, Suzie.
Mattie! Warren!
- [gasping]
- You all right?
I'm gonna go down and get Matt.
Hey, Warren, you gotta get out.
Come with me, right? Take a deep breath.
- [Kate] Matt. Where's Matt?
- Matt? Where's Matt?
Matt! Mattie?
[Matt] Here! I'm here.
It's stuck.
[Luke] This way, this way, this way.
OK, follow me.
[Matt] You all right? You OK?
Yeah? You OK?
- Let's get out of the water.
- Yeah. Yeah, sure.
- Gonna have to push him.
- [Matt] Yeah, OK.
[men] One, two, three!
[Warren] Up you get.
[Matt] All right, who's next?
- [Warren] You got me?
- [Luke] Come on.
OK, here we go. More hands.
- You all right, Suze?
- Yeah.
Fuck. Look at that.
Keel's been ripped off.
- [Suzie] You OK?
- [Matt] It's OK. You all right?
Yeah.
- What happened?
- [Luke] Don't know.
Must have hit something.
Reef. A whale.
The bulkheads are fucked.
OK, guys, I don't think
we should stay here.
There's a current.
We're drifting further out to sea.
The boat's fucked.
I don't think it's gonna stay afloat.
And when we do sink, we're in the water,
just further from land.
- It mightn't sink.
- Well, is there an EPlRB?
- What's an EPlRB?
- A distress beacon. Yeah, there is.
Yeah, but it's an old one, so you need
a plane to fly over to get a signal.
- We're not in a flight path.
- How do you know that?
Seen any planes in the last few days?
OK, I'm not saying we should
try and swim to the mainland,
but I reckon
we could make Turtle lsland.
No.
- What are you doing?
- Point the 12 at the sun.
Split the angle between the 12
and the hour hand. That's north.
So, we're here, right?
Turtle lsland is here.
Now, we weren't going straight there,
because there's a reef here.
But with the current, I reckon
if we swim north, we'll hit the island.
- How far would we have to swim?
- Uh... 10, 12 miles.
Good luck.
I've fished these waters, mate.
I know what's out there.
I'm not getting in that water.
What makes you think
they're not gonna come here?
There's all sorts of shit
starting to rot.
I don't wanna argue with you, mate,
honestly I don't. I just...
I'm not getting in the water.
All right, look, yeah,
there might be sharks, I don't know.
What I do know
is that there's land over there
and the longer we sit here,
the further we get away from it.
We either swim for it
and try and save ourselves,
while we've still got enough strength,
or we can stay here
and hope the boat doesn't sink
and that someone comes for us.
And they'd better come soon, because
otherwise we'll die of dehydration.
I'm not a great swimmer.
I don't think I could swim that far.
Yeah, no. Me neither.
OK.
All right. I'll go down below and see
what I can find to keep us afloat.
You need a hand?
Yeah, if you're in the water,
I'll pass out whatever I find, yeah?
- You OK?
- Yeah.
- Here goes.
- OK.
[thudding]
[Matt] Luke! Luke!
Hey, Luke! Luke!
[Warren] Luke, mate, can you hear me?
[Matt] There's something in the water.
Hey! Luke, quickly, get out! It's close!
Get out now! Get out!
[Warren] Luke, there's something
in the water! Could be a shark!
[Matt] Luke, come on! Hurry up!
Get out! Luke!
Luke!
Something broke the surface, over there.
- Well, what was it?
- I don't know, but it was big.
All right.
I've still got to find the EPlRB.
So unless you see a really big shark,
don't warn me.
[Luke] See you soon.
[thudding]
[thudding continues]
- [Kate] You all right?
- Yeah, I'm fine.
Found it.
- [Luke] You know how to kick it off?
- It's good, mate.
Yeah? OK, great.
Try that.
- For you.
- Thanks, mate.
- What? What's the matter?
- You'll look like a seal in that.
Sharks love seals.
Mate, you don't wanna come,
that's your business.
Don't go scaring everyone else,
all right?
Maybe we should wait.
OK, it's your choice.
Look, I know
this is a difficult decision,
but it's really easy
not to get found out here.
This boat's gonna sink
and it's gonna sink soon.
There's land over there and that's
where I think we should be going.
I'm going with Luke.
Me too.
That's yours.
Here you go. Take that. Yours.
- I'm not going.
- Hey?
I'm gonna stay here.
It's a better option
than staying on the boat.
What, swimming to an island
you can't see?
Kate...
OK.
- OK, that's for you.
- Thanks.
Are you sure about this?
Yeah?
- We'll send someone as soon as we can.
- OK.
- OK?
- Yep.
See you, mate.
See you soon.
Bye.
- See you back there.
- Definitely.
What are you doing?
You know he knows the ocean
more than any of us.
- Come on, Katie, come with us.
- I can't.
I just... I just can't.
- See you later, sis.
- Bye.
Yeah?
OK, let's go.
- You look after her for me, all right?
- I will, don't worry. We're good.
OK, so let's stick together.
We're gonna get tired,
but if we just stay at a steady pace,
we'll get there, yeah?
Apart from that, relax and enjoy.
It's a once in a lifetime.
Let's go.
[Luke] Hey, guys!
- Not so much splashing.
- Did you see something?
- No.
- [Kate] Hey! Hey, wait!
Wait! I'm gonna come with you!
Come on. Come with us.
- No.
- Are you sure?
Yeah, no, you go. I'll be right.
This is nuts.
I hope you're right about this.
You're not the only one.
Guys, don't worry, we'll make it.
We'll get there.
- Here, take this.
- Are you sure?
Yeah, it's all right.
We'll share this one.
Thanks.
Hey, guys. We're tired.
So we focus our energy, huh?
lmagine there's a guy with a huge rope
pulling us towards the island.
- Or towards my bed.
- Mm.
- There's always the last resort.
- What's that?
When I'm at the gym and I'm trying
to break through the pain barrier,
I imagine that I'm having sex.
[laughter]
While you're doing weights,
you're imagining you're screwing?
Notjust screwing.
There's foreplay as well.
Well, isn't there?
Not often.
Oh, come on!
Don't listen to her.
- Shit. What was that?
- What?
[splashing]
- [splashing]
- [Suzie] Oh!
What is it?
Can't see anything.
I think it's a school of small fish.
- [Suzie] What are they doing?
- [Luke] I don't know.
OK, let's keep going.
[Luke] Come on.
- [Kate] What is it?
- Looks like a shell.
- It's a turtle shell.
- Yeah, I think you're right.
A turtle?
Hey, Matt.
Mattie.
Oh, fuck!
Let's get the fuck out of here.
Come on, Suze.
Hey, we can't stay here.
Come on.
I don't wanna stretch my legs out,
I really don't.
- OK, all right.
- I can't move.
It's all right. Listen, we've gotta go.
So do you want me to go behind you?
[Matt] Come on, love.
I'll go behind you, OK?
[Matt] I got you.
- You OK?
- Yeah.
- That was a big turtle.
- Fuck, yeah.
[splashing]
What was that?
- What?
- Over there, I saw something.
[Kate] I can't see anything.
- Suzie, you're freaking me out.
- [Luke] What's the matter?
- There's something here.
- We have to keep going.
- There's something following us.
- Suze, this is the ocean, OK?
There's a million things out here, bub.
We've gotta keep going.
We've gotta get going.
Come on. Gotta go, all right?
- It's all right.
- There!
- All right, Suze, listen...
- I'm sure I saw something and it's big!
- OK, so what did you see?
- I don't know. There! There, look.
I can't see anything.
Over there.
- Did you see something?
- Don't know. Maybe.
- I told you.
- [Kate] What was it?
- [Matt] Was it a shark?
- I don't know, OK?
Let's keep going.
- OK, it's a shark.
- How big?
It's big. It's all right. Come together.
- [Luke] I can't see it.
- [screaming]
Get in together.
[Matt] Can you see it?
Luke, can you see it?
I think it's gone.
I can't see it anywhere.
[screaming]
Let's go. Let's go.
We've gotta go this way.
[Luke] This way.
It's OK, it's OK.
I can't see it. It's moved away.
It's OK. I can't see it. I can't see it.
You need to calm down.
I can't see it. It's OK.
It's OK. It's OK.
You have to stay calm.
[sobbing]
Katie. Katie.
Katie. Katie. Katie.
Take some deep breaths with me.
Deep breaths. Come on.
You'll be all right. It's not gonna
get you. It's not gonna get you.
Take a deep breath.
It's gonna be all right.
[Luke] Deep breath.
That's it. That's it.
Matt. Matt.
Hey, Mattie.
Matt.
- Matt!
- [Kate] Matt!
- Matthew!
Matt! Matt!
[Luke] Matt! Mattie!
Matt!
[Suzie screaming]
There he is. Mattie!
[sobs]
[Matt] No! Go! Go!
My fucking leg's gone!
No! Go! No!
My leg's gone. You gotta...
No, you gotta go!
- You gotta leave me!
- [Kate] It's OK, it's OK.
- Swim. I'm useless to you.
- [Kate] No, you're coming with us.
- [Kate] Mattie, it's OK.
- He's gonna... He's gonna come back.
Mattie, Mattie, Look at me.
It's OK. Just stay with me.
- Quick, before he... before he...
- [Kate] No, no, no. No, no, no.
Mattie. Mattie.
Matt. Mattie.
Matt. Matt, come on, come on.
Wake up. Wake up.
Please wake up. Wake up.
Wake up, wake up.
[sobs]
Come on. Mattie, wake up!
Wake up! Please wake up!
Wake up. Please.
Katie!
[Luke] Katie, get out of there now!
Oh, God. I love you.
Katie!
- Come on!
- Oh, God. I love you.
[sobs]
Hey.
[Kate] Come on.
Come on. Come on.
Come on.
- Did you say something?
- No.
- What?
- You said something.
It's gonna come back, isn't it?
lsn't it?
Didn't you say
we'd be there in three hours?
How are we gonna get there now?
We're lost in the middle of the ocean
in the middle of the fucking night!
- [Kate] Suzie...
- We never should have listened to you.
We should have stayed on the boat
with Warren.
And now Matt's dead!
And soon we're gonna be too!
- We're fucked! We're so fucked!
- [Kate] Suzie!
[Suzie] We're so...
I'm sorry about Matt.
And I'm sorry about all of this.
[Kate] Luke, it's not your fault.
It's not your fault.
You didn't make us come with you.
It's all right.
It's all right. Hey.
[splashing]
- [Kate] What was that?
- [splashing]
[splashing]
[Kate] Oh, my God.
Come together. Come together.
[Suzie] Oh, my God!
I don't wanna die!
Please! Help us!
Oh, God, somebody help us!
Hey.
- Hey.
- Look.
Oh. Hey.
Suze.
Look.
[Suzie laughs]
[Kate] Whoo!
OK, be careful, huh? It's very sharp.
Oh, it's so good to be out of the water.
It's not Turtle lsland, but it's land.
Let's keep going, then.
Yeah.
- Oh, I'm so sore.
- Me too.
What?
I don't know.
[Luke] Get back.
Oh! It's a fucking dolphin.
[laughs]
Moving pretty fast.
The current must have picked up.
Finally the current is helping.
Is that the dolphin?
Suzie! Suzie!
Suzie!
[screaming]
[whimpers]
Oh, fuck.
It's OK. Come on.
Come on.
Oh, my God.
Poor Suzie.
It's the same one, isn't it?
I think so.
It is. I know it is.
There's some more reef.
I think we should go.
Luke! Luke!
Luke!
Come on. Come on.
Come on, Luke.
Come on. Come on, let's go.
I... No.
- You OK?
- Yeah.
My... My foot, it's bleeding.
[Luke] Oh, shit.
Sorry.
Thanks.
It's OK.
I love you, Luke.
I love you too.
- You ready?
- No.
Me neither.
Let's go.
[screams]
Swim. Fucking swim!
[Luke] Come on, babe.
Come on.
Come on! Go!
[Kate] Come on!
Go! Go!
Pull me up! Pull me up!
Take me! Take me!
Come on. I can't!
- Come on! Come on!
- Get me up!
Pull me up! Pull me up!
Luke!
Please come home.
Please come home. Please.
[screams]